JOSHUA PALAMUTTAM

https://github.com/joshpal
97 \diamond https://Joshua Palamuttam.com San Jose, CA 95138

 $(408) \cdot 841 \cdot 6194 \diamond joshpal97@gmail.com$

SUMMARY

A highly-motivated computer professional, who graduated with a Computer Science degree from Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology '19, with the enthusiasm to accept new challenges. Currently working for Kaiser Permanente (San Jose, CA), previously worked for DMI (Indianapolis, IN). Both positions have given me hands-on work experience as a software engineer working on application design, development, and quality assurance.

EDUCATION

Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology

2015 - 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

EXPERIENCE

Kaiser Permanente Genetics

February 2020 - Present

Junior Dot Net Analyst, San Jose, CA

- · Main purpose was to do RD for different applications used by the Genetics Department
- \cdot Responsibilities for this job include gathering requirements along with developing and supporting applications
- \cdot Made applications with the Kaiser tech stack of primarily .Net Core MVC applications, with a SQL Database
- · Occasionally made Batch Files, or Excel VBA scripts to aid Lab Technicians in thier duties

 DMI

 May 2019

Software Engineer, Indianapolis, IN

May 2019 - February 2020

- · Helped create a POC for Kar Global to optimize lot operations at a car auction site, using Angular, Node.js, AWS serverless, SQL (1 month)
- · Helped build a physics engine called ISCAAN for Allison Transmission to simulate a transmission (6 months)
- · The majority of Allison Transmission's proprietary math was done using C++, which was then passed to a Angular, .Net Core, SQL stack, using Entity Framework Core
- · Because of ISCAAN's large nature, the project was designed to use a hexagonal software architecture
- · Built Microsoft Teams Chat bot for DMI, using LUIS an Azure Cognitive Service (NLP) with a .Net Core back end
- · All projects used Azure Devops to adhere to SAFe agile practices, such as CI/CD, unit and integration testing

PROJECTS

Compile.io (Angular, Spring Boot, MongoDb, Docker)

2018-2019

- · My Senior Project, tasked to build a scalable website that automatically grades student submitted code
- · Code was submitted through the Angular front-end, taken to our Java Spring backend, processed in a docker container, and stored in MongoDB.
- · Gathered requirements from professors, and wrote documentation that can be viewed in my github
- · Followed Agile methodologies, with CI/CD, 2 week sprints, feature branching strategy, and unit testing

Stock Market Analysis through Twitter (Python)

Spring 2019

- · The purpose of this project was to figure out how a companys twitter handle and companys CEO twitter handle affected the companys stock
- · Performed Latent Semantic Analysis on tweets for those twitter handles
- · Pre-processed data by removing stop words, duplicate tweets, and special characters
- · Used cross-validation, and Naive Bayes to predict the Stock Market
- · The stock data was recieved through quandl, and the tweets were recieved through tweepy

Full stack website, College Cookbook (Javascript, Firebase, MongoDB)

Fall 2017

- · The website can be found at this link: https://college-cookbook-jkl.firebaseapp.com/login.html or github
- · Developed and Integrated a MongoDB database for the back end and deployed front end through Firebase
- · Features: posting to twitter, emailing recipes, inputting recipes into the database, and secure login

SKILLS

Programming Languages
JavaScript, Typescript, C#, Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, Python
Frameworks
Angular, Node.js, Spring, .Net Core, Entity Framework Core

AWC. Agure Daving, Declar, Cit. Vigual Studie, Vigual Studie, Vigual Studie

Tools AWS, Azure Devops, Docker, Git, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code

Certifications SAFe 4.6